Guide to Don Oberdorfer's Mansfield Biography Research Papers 1918-2003
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Don Oberdorfer's Mansfield Biography Research Papers
1918-2003
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana--Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 590
Oberdorfer, Don B. 1931-2015
14.0 linear feet and 72 audiocassette tapes
The collection contains materials related to the research and writing of Oberdorfer’s book, Senator Mansfield: The Extraordinary Life of a Great American Statesman and Diplomat (Smithsonian Books, 2003).
Biographical Note
Don Oberdorfer was born May 28, 1931 in Atlanta, Georgia. He graduated from Princeton University in 1952 and served as a United States Army lieutenant in Korea from 1953 to 1954. He began his journalistic career on the Charlotte Observer in 1955, becoming the paper’s Washington correspondent in 1958. He was a Washington editor at the Saturday Evening Post (1961-1965) and a national correspondent for the Knight Newspapers chain (1965-1968). During his twenty-five years at the Washington Post (1968-1993), he worked as a White House correspondent, Northeast Asia correspondent, and diplomatic correspondent.
Oberdorfer authored of five books and numerous newspaper and magazine articles. His books include Tet! (Doubleday, 1971; Da Capo Press, 1984) and The Two Koreas: A Contemporary History (Addison-Wesley, 1997). He retired from the The Post in 1993, then became the Distinguished Journalist in Residence and Adjunct Professor of International Relations at Johns Hopkins University's Nitze School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS) in Washington, D.C. In 2006, he founded the U.S.-Korea Institute (USKI) at at the Nitze School, which he also chaired until 2013 when he became chairman emeritus. Don Oberdorfer died on July 23, 2015.
This collection contains materials related to the research and writing of Oberdorfer’s book, Senator Mansfield: The Extraordinary Life of a Great American Statesman and Diplomat (Smithsonian Books, 2003), which won the D.B. Hardeman Prize in 2003. The book is a biography of Mike Mansfield, a United States House Representative and Senator from Montana who also served as ambassador to Japan during the Carter and Reagan administrations. The collection provides access to the documents and other materials that Oberdorfer cites in his book, Senator Mansfield. The research materials include photocopies and summaries from books and articles about Mansfield and related historical topics, as well as primary documents gathered from archival repositories like the presidential libraries of John F. Kennedy and Lyndon B. Johnson. The research materials provide glimpses into Mansfield’s personal life and public career through copies of correspondence, photographs, and other materials from the private collections of Mansfield family members.
The collection includes summaries of Oberdorfer’s conversations with Mansfield’s family, colleagues, and friends and some drafts of chapters from Oberdorfer’s book. Manuscript drafts and writings related to the book are filed with the research materials. The collection also contains recorded interviews with Mansfield and Mansfield's colleagues that Oberdorfer conducted as research for the Mansfield biography, as well as non-interview audio recordings related to Oberdorfer's research.
This collection is divided into four series:
Series I: Research Files, 14.0 linear foot, 1918-2003
Series II: Audio Interviews with Mansfield, 21 audio cassettes, 1998-2001
Series III: Audio Interviews with Mansfield's Colleagues, 41 audio cassettes, 1998-2001 - RESTRICTED
Series IV: Audio Recordings, 10 audio cassettes, 1980-2000 and undated
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula. Most of audio in Series III is currently restricted pending review by the speakers or their family regarding appropriate access to the interviews. Contact Archives and Special Collections for details.
Gift of Don Oberdorfer, 2004, 2005 and 2009.
All of the cassettes in Series II, most of the cassettes in Series III, and some of the cassettes in Series IV have been digitized for access and preservation purposes.
Princeton University holds a collection of Don Oberdorfer’s papers related to another of his publications.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Mansfield, Mike--1903- Biography; Mansfield, Mike--1903---Interviews
Oral histories--Montana; Biographies
Montana; Oral Histories; International Relations
Senator Mansfield: The Extraordinary Life of a Great American Statesman and Diplomat
- Research Files, 1918-2003; Series I; 14.0 linear foot
  The collection includes summaries of Oberdorfer’s conversations with Mansfield’s family, colleagues, and friends and some drafts of chapters from Oberdorfer’s book. Manuscript drafts and writings related to the book are filed with the research materials.
  This series maintains Oberdofer’s original arrangement of the files.
  - Mansfield biographies, undated (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Mansfield honesty, frugality, 1963-2001 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Correspondence, book substance, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - M [Mansfield] Death, obits etc, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Mansfield’s funeral, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - MM [Mike Mansfield] statement lists, 1965, 1976 and undated (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Bibliography, 1944-1999 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Questionnaires of M [Mansfield], 1971-1975 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - MM [Mike Mansfield] Oral histories and correspondence, 1964-1986 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Man [Mansfield], 1937-2000 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - M [Mansfield] – family and friends – (Montana, New York), 1909-2001 and undated (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Maureen, 1999-2002 and undated (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Mansfield, Anne, 1966-2000 and undated (Box-folder 2/2)
  - M [Mansfield] interviews – my tapes (transcripts), 1998-2001 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - M [Mansfield] Health and Maureen Health, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Interviews and correspondence with others, 1977-2001 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - M [Mansfield] interviews with others, 1976-1991 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Time Magazine interviews, 1957 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Senators and M [Mansfield], 1978-1991 and undated (Box-folder 2/8)
  - M [Mansfield] – interviews with Senators (Jeffrey Safford papers), 1976-1977 (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Montana Representative/Senator, 1960-1972 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Montana Politics, undated (Box-folder 2/11)
  - M [Mansfield] – Reference, 1976-1997 and undated (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Great Falls, 1996-2000 and undated (Box-folder 3/2)
  - M [Mansfield]’s Military Records, 1919-2000 and undated (Box-folder 3/3)
  - M [Mansfield] Military World War I, 1918-2001 and undated (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Man [Mansfield] Memoirs, 1988-2001 and undated (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Butte, 1944-2001 and undated (Box-folder 3/6)
  - University of Montana, 1934-2003 and undated (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Kawai, 1951-2001 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - In Congress – 1943 etc, 1943-2000 and undated (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Campaigns (1940, 1942), 1939-2000 and undated (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Campaigns (1946, 1948, 1950), 1946-1981 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - 1952 Campaign, 1951-2002 and undated (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Campaigns (1958, 1964), 1958-1964 and undated (Box-folder 4/4)
  - 1970 Campaign, 1970-2001 and undated (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Eighteen-year-old vote, 1970-1999 (Box-folder 4/6)
  - M [Mansfield] – Korea, 1948-1991 and undated (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Gun Control (1968), 1968-1991 and undated (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Rowe correspondence, 1949-2000 and undated (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Engelhard, 1958-2002 and undated (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Frank Valeo (Oral history), 1985-1986 (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Frank Valeo (interviews), 1998-1999 and undated (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Ludwick materials, 1995 and undated (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Anne Mansfield materials, 1960-1976 and undated (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Vietnam (1950s), 1949-1974 and undated (Box-folder 5/5)
  - Foreign Policy, Statements etc. (1953-60), 1951-1960 (Box-folder 5/6)
  - 1953 Trip, 1953-1999 and undated (Box-folder 5/7)
  - 1954 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - 1954 Trip (Box-folder 6/2)
  - 1954 Manila Conference, 1954-2001 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - 1954 Manila Conference, 1953-1988 and undated (Box-folder 6/4)
  - 1955 Trip and 1955, 1955-1957 and undated (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Diem 1955 Materials, 1955-1991 and undated (Box-folder 7/1)
  - M [Mansfield] and Diem (General), 1956-1998 and undated (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Diem (Pre-1954), 1951-2001 and undated (Box-folder 7/3)
  - Diem (1954 – 1960), 1945-1998 and undated (Box-folder 7/4)
  - Dulles (1950), 1953-2000 and undated (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Lansdale papers, 1950-2001 (Box-folder 7/6)
  - M [Mansfield] Foreign Policy Vietnam (early 1950s), 1952-2002 and undated (Box-folder 7/7)
  - China (1922 Marines), 1922-1998 and undated (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Tientsin, 1922-2000 and undated (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Tientsin Photographs, 2000 (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Tientsin 2, 1918 and undated (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Tientsin 3, 1920-1999 and undated (Box-folder 8/4)
  - China 1944 Preliminaries, 1944-1999 and undated (Box-folder 8/5)
  - China Trip 1944 Background, 1943-1999 and undated (Box-folder 8/6)
  - China Trip (1944), 1944-1999 and undated (Box-folder 8/7)
  - China Trip 44 (Diary, Reports), 1942-2000 and undated (Box-folder 9/1)
  - China Trip 44 (Diary, Reports), 1944-1999 and undated (Box-folder 9/2)
  - Post China Trip (1944-1945), 1945-1972 and undated (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Mansfield speeches (1945) (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Revisions to chapter "Mission in China", 2000 and undated (Box-folder 9/5)
  - MM [Mike Mansfield], Truman, 1940-2000 (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Philosophical Philosophies, China Policy, Latin American Study Trip, 1946-2000 and undated (Box-folder 9/7)
  - Surrender of Japan, 1945-1999 and undated (Box-folder 9/8)
  - Revision I, Truman, 1945-2002 and undated (Box-folder 10/1)
  - 1947 Europe Journal (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Congressional Record index, 1943-1976 (Box-folder 10/3)
  - MM [Mike Mansfield] JFK [John F. Kennedy] (1960-1963), 1960-1986 and undated (Box-folder 10/4)
  - China 1960-61 etc, 1958-1999 and undated (Box-folder 10/5)
  - JFK [John F. Kennedy]- MM [Mike Mansfield] Chronological file, 1960-1998 and undated (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Foreign Affairs (Cuba 1961-1962), 1961-1963 and undated (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Germany-JFK [John F. Kennedy], 1959-1968 and undated (Box-folder 10/8)
  - Intelligence Oversight, 1953-1977 and undated (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Majority Leader (1961-1963), 1960-1998 and undated (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Majority Leader (1961-1963), 1962-1997 and undated (Box-folder 11/3)
  - Laos (1961- 1962), 1954-2000 and undated (Box-folder 11/4)
  - Laos (1961- 1962), 1961-1998 and undated (Box-folder 11/5)
  - Vietnam 1962-JFK [John F. Kennedy] withdrawal issue, 1962-1997 and undated (Box-folder 11/6)
  - Vietnam 1962-JFK [John F. Kennedy] withdrawal issue, 1962-1998 and undated (Box-folder 11/7)
  - Diem (1960s including 1963), 1962-1998 and undated (Box-folder 11/8)
  - Rometsch case, 1963-2000 and undated (Box-folder 12/1)
  - MM [Mike Mansfield] JFK [John F. Kennedy] Personal, 1954-1988 and undated (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Vietnam 1962 (Prelude), 1961-1962 and undated (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Vietnam 1962 (Prelude), 1960-1963 (Box-folder 12/4)
  - M [Mansfield] JFK [John F. Kennedy] 1962 Vietnam trip (Box-folder 12/5)
  - M [Mansfield] JFK [John F. Kennedy] 1962 Vietnam trip, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 12/6)
  - Vietnam-1962 JFK [John F. Kennedy] follow up, 1962-1963 and undated (Box-folder 13/1)
  - Chapter VIII revisions-JFK [John F. Kennedy] era, 1961-2001 and undated (Box-folder 13/2)
  - LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] (1963) (Box-folder 13/3)
  - LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] (1964), 1964-2002 (Box-folder 13/4)
  - Majority Leader (1964-1968), 1966-2001 (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Civil Rights Majority Leader, 1964-1987 and undated (Box-folder 13/6)
  - LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson]-MM [Mike Mansfield] relationship (Vietnam), 1963-2000 and undated (Box-folder 14/1)
  - Tonkin Gulf (1964), 1964-2000 and undated (Box-folder 14/2)
  - Patronage politics-LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] era, 1960-2001 and undated (Box-folder 14/3)
  - M [Mansfield] Fulbright 1965-1966, 1965-2002 and undated (Box-folder 14/4)
  - Foreign Relations of the United States excerpts, 1958-1968 (Box-folder 14/5)
  - Richard B. Russell materials, 1963-1999 and undated (Box-folder 14/6)
  - M [Mansfield]-LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] (1965), 1965 and undated (Box-folder 14/7)
  - M [Mansfield]-LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] (1965), 1965 and undated (Box-folder 15/1)
  - Pleiku, 1965 (Box-folder 15/2)
  - LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson]-M [Mansfield] Personal, 1964-1988 and undated (Box-folder 15/3)
  - LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson]-M [Mansfield] Personal, 1955-1998 and undated (Box-folder 15/4)
  - 1965 Trip, 1954-2002 and undated (Box-folder 15/5)
  - 1965 Trip (Box-folder 15/6)
  - LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] (1966), 1965-1967 (Box-folder 16/1)
  - 1966-1967 including United Nations materials, 1966-1967 and undated (Box-folder 16/2)
  - 1966-1967 including United Nations materials, 1966-1967 and undated (Box-folder 16/3)
  - LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] (1967), 1967-1998 and undated (Box-folder 16/4)
  - Speeches (1961–1967), 1963-1968 (Box-folder 16/5)
  - Johnson I revisions, 1965-2001 and undated (Box-folder 16/6)
  - Johnson (other materials), undated (Box-folder 17/1)
  - LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] Daily Diary, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 17/2)
  - Troops Europe (1966-1968), 1966-1968 and undated (Box-folder 17/3)
  - M [Mansfield] – LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] meeting 3/27/1968, 1968-2000 and undated (Box-folder 17/4)
  - M [Mansfield] – LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] meeting 3/27/1968, 1968-2000 and undated (Box-folder 17/5)
  - LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] tapes, 1964-2001 and undated (Box-folder 17/6)
  - LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] Congress and Foreign Policy, 1968-2002 (Box-folder 17/7)
  - LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] 1968 Pre-speech, 1968-1996 and undated (Box-folder 17/8)
  - LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] Bombing halt and troops, 1968-1998 and undated (Box-folder 17/9)
  - LBJ [Lyndon B. Johnson] politics, 1968-1999 and undated (Box-folder 18/1)
  - Post-March 1968, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 18/2)
  - Meetings, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 18/3)
  - Walt W. Rostow, 1999 (Box-folder 18/4)
  - Nixon (1969), 1969-1991 (Box-folder 18/5)
  - M [Mansfield] Asia Trip (1969), 1969-1999 and undated (Box-folder 18/6)
  - M [Mansfield] Asia Trip (1969), 1969 and undated (Box-folder 18/7)
  - Nixon (1969-1970), 1969-1970 and undated (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Nixon (1970), 1970-1977 and undated (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Nixon (1970), 1970-1988 and undated (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Nixon (1971), 1971-2001 and undated (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Nixon (1971), 1971-2002 and undated (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Nixon (1972), 1972-1978 and undated (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Nixon (1972) (Box-folder 19/6)
  - M [Mansfield] Amendment (Europe 1971), 1961-1999 and undated (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Prince Sihanouk (Cambodia/China 1969), 1969-1999 and undated (Box-folder 20/2)
  - MM [Mike Mansfield] Cambodia, 1970-1998 and undated (Box-folder 20/3)
  - MM [Mike Mansfield] China Miscellaneous, 1942-2001 and undated (Box-folder 20/4)
  - China material, 1971 and undated (Box-folder 20/5)
  - Cambodia materials from Julio A. Jeldres, 1969-2002 and undated (Box-folder 20/6)
  - Early 1972 (China leadup) (Box-folder 20/7)
  - 1972 Trip in China, 1972 and undated (Box-folder 21/1)
  - 1972 China trip (Hildenbrand and Scott) (Box-folder 21/2)
  - China trip 1972 follow-up, 1968-1986 and undated (Box-folder 21/3)
  - 1973 China trip idea, 1972-2002 and undated (Box-folder 21/4)
  - Nixon (1973), 1972-1977 and undated (Box-folder 21/5)
  - Watergate, 1973-2002 and undated (Box-folder 21/6)
  - 1974 China Trip, 1974-1975 and undated (Box-folder 22/1)
  - 1974 Nixon (Mansfield) (Box-folder 22/2)
  - Nixon (Mansfield, General), 1969-2000 and undated (Box-folder 22/3)
  - MM [Mike Mansfield] Vietnam (General), 1954-1986 and undated (Box-folder 22/4)
  - Majority Leader (General), 1967-2001 and undated (Box-folder 22/5)
  - Ford (General), undated (Box-folder 22/6)
  - Ford (1974) (Box-folder 22/7)
  - Ford (1975) (Box-folder 22/8)
  - Fall of Saigon 1975 (Mayaguez), 1975, 2002 and undated (Box-folder 22/9)
  - 1976 China trip, 1976 and undated (Box-folder 23/1)
  - Ford (1976), 1975-1976 (Box-folder 23/2)
  - Ford M [Mansfield] contacts, 1974 (Box-folder 23/3)
  - Mansfield photos (not used), undated (Box-folder 23/4)
  - Miscellaneous newspapers, 1999 and 2001 (Box-folder 23/5)
  - Reports by Senator Mansfield, 1967-1975 (Box-folder 23/6)
  - Reports by Senator Mansfield, 1976 (Box-folder 24/1)
  - Senate tributes to Mike Mansfield, 1976-1976 (Box-folder 24/2)
  - Mansfield's FBI file, obtained at Oberdorfer's request, 1943-2000 (Box-folder 24/3)
  - 1972 China trip, [Senator Hugh] Scott materials (Box-folder 24/4)
  - Japan - reference, 1985-2000 (Box-folder 24/5)
  - Japan - used materials, 1977-1993 (Box-folder 24/6)
  - Mansfield - Japan pre-appointment, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 24/7)
  - Mansfield interviews, Japan, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 25/1)
  - Japan - Ambassador/personal, 1977-2000 (Box-folder 25/2)
  - Embassy, 1978-2003 (Box-folder 25/3)
  - Japan - criticisms of Mansfield and reports that he is leaving [Japan], 1980-1988 (Box-folder 25/4)
  - Japan - Reagan re-appointment and retirement appointments, 1980-1998 (Box-folder 25/5)
  - Japan - Mansfield and Reagan, 1985-2002 (Box-folder 25/6)
  - Japan - Nakasone, 1982-1998 (Box-folder 25/7)
  - Japan - Assessments, 1978-2000 (Box-folder 25/8)
  - Mansfield - Japan, 81-82 (Reagan), 1981-1998 (Box-folder 25/9)
  - Japan - Mansfield, 83-84, 1983-1998 (Box-folder 25/10)
  - Japan - Mansfield, 85-86, 1985-1996 (Box-folder 25/11)
  - Japan - Mansfield, 87-88, 1987-1999 (Box-folder 25/12)
  - Japan - submarine [USS George Washington] incident 1981, 1981-1999 (Box-folder 26/1)
  - [Japan] - auto [manufacture] 80-81, 1980-1998 (Box-folder 26/2)
  - Robert Strauss [and Ambassador Mansfield], 1977-2000 (Box-folder 26/3)
  - Japan - Defense issues, 1977-1999 (Box-folder 26/4)
  - Mansfield retirement reports, 1988 (Box-folder 26/5)
  - Japan - economy, 1978-2003 (Box-folder 26/6)
  - New York Times and Congressional Record indexes of speeches [and articles], 1977-1989 (Box-folder 26/7)
  - Japan - [research], undated (Box-folder 26/8)
  - [Mansfield's] congressional retirement '76, 1975-1999 (Box-folder 27/1)
  - 1976 China trip, Asia trips, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 27/2)
  - Japan, [Mansfield] and President Carter, 1977-1998 (Box-folder 27/3)
  - President Carter library materials, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 27/4)
  - Japan - Tokai Mura '77, 1977-2003 (Box-folder 27/5)
  - [Michael] Pillsbury, 1978-1998 (Box-folder 27/6)
  - Facts on File indexes, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 27/7)
  - [White House and National Security Council general correspondence and news clippings], 1977 (Box-folder 27/8)
  - [White House and National Security Council general correspondence and news clippings], 1978 (Box-folder 28/1)
  - [White House and National Security Council general correspondence and news clippings], 1979 (Box-folder 28/2)
  - [White House and National Security Council general correspondence and news clippings], 1980 (Box-folder 28/3)
  - [Ambassadors and Japan] post Mike Mansfield, 1989 (Box-folder 28/4)
  - Mansfield, post retirement, 1983-1999 (Box-folder 28/5)
  - Kambuja, Cambodian magazine with article about Mike Mansfield's visit to Cambodia, 1969 (Box-folder 28/6)
  - Oberdorfer's raw transcripts of the interviews he conducted with Mike Mansfield (OH 391), 1998-2001 (Box 28/7)
- Audio Interviews with Mansfield, 1998-2001; Series II; 21 audio cassettes
  This series contains oral history interviews Oberdorfer conducted with Mike Mansfield as research for Oberdorfer’s biography on Mansfield.
  These audio interviews were assigned an oral history collection name, Don Oberdorfer Interviews with Mike Mansfield Oral History Project and given collection number OH 391, to facilitate discovery and access.
  There is no recorded audio OH 391-001 cassette tape. The interview consists of Don Oberdorfer’s notes taken during his first unrecorded meetings with Mansfield about the biography. A full transcript of these notes is available on ScholarWorks.
  This series is organized numerically by cassette number.
  Electronic copies of the audio are available from the University of Montana's Archives and Special Collections as oral history project OH 391.
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, July 24, 1998 (Cassette OH 391-002)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, August 28, 1998 (Cassette OH 391-003)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, September 10, 1998 (Cassette OH 391-004)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, October 8, 1998 (Cassette OH 391-005)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, October 29, 1998 (Cassette OH 391-006)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, April 9, 1999 (Cassette OH 391-007)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, July 24, 1999 (Cassette OH 391-008)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, August 18, 1999 (Cassette OH 391-009)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, September 9, 1999 (Cassette OH 391-010)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, October 20, 1999 (Cassette OH 391-011)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, October 23, 1999 (Cassette OH 391-012)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, November 26, 1999 (Cassette OH 391-013)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, January 27, 2000 (Cassette OH 391-014)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, February 18, 2000 (Cassette OH 391-015)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, April 20, 2000 (Cassette OH 391-016)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, May 11, 2000 (Cassette OH 391-017)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, July 21, 2000 (Cassette OH 391-018)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, October 10, 2000 (Cassette OH 391-019)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, November 10, 2000 (Cassette OH 391-020)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, June 1, 2001 (Cassette OH 391-021)
  - Interview with Mike Mansfield, July 20, 2001 (Cassette OH 391-022)
- Audio Interviews with Mansfield's Colleagues, 1998-2001; Series III; 41 audio cassettes
  This series contains oral history interviews Oberdorfer conducted with Mike Mansfield’s friends and colleagues about Mansfield’s personal life and political career as research for Oberdorfer’s biography on Mansfield.
  These audio interviews were assigned an oral history collection name, Don Oberdorfer Interviews about Mike Mansfield Oral History Project and given collection number OH 460, to facilitate discovery and access.
  Most items in this series are restricted and restrictions are noted at the item level.
  Most of the audio in this series was digitized for preservation and access purposes.
  - Interview with Francis "Frank" Valeo, August 26, 1998 (Cassette III-1)
  - Interview with Francis "Frank" Valeo, August 26, 1998 (Cassette III-2)
  - Interview with Francis "Frank" Valeo, September 10, 1998 (Cassette III-3)
  - Interview with William "Bill" Clark - RESTRICTED, August 29, 1998 (Cassette III-4)
  - Interview with Dan Russel - RESTRICTED, September 1, 1998; Self-recorded reminiscence about Mansfield. (Cassette III-5)
  - Interview with William "Bill" Sherman - RESTRICTED, September 16, 1998 (Cassette III-6)
  - Interview with William "Bill" Conrad Gibbons - RESTRICTED, October 15, 1998 (Cassette III-7)
  - Interview with George Christian - RESTRICTED, January 1, 1999 (Cassette III-8)
  - Interview with Roy Mylnarchik - RESTRICTED, January 7, 1999 (Cassette III-9)
  - Interview with Walt Rostow - RESTRICTED, January 13, 1999 (Cassette III-10)